Clara E. Sipprell Papers
Clara E. Sipprell Papers
- Photographs
  - Character studies
    - Roxanne, 1963 (Oversize 2)
    - Russian nobleman, 1935 (Oversize 2)
    - Sisters, 1930 (Oversize 2)
    - Son of a Liberian King, 1940 (Oversize 2)
      See also Dancer, Liberia.
    - A Sprig of Pussywillow *, 1930 (Oversize 2)
    - Tarascan Indian, Mexico, 1932 (Oversize 2)
    - Three Years Old, 1931 (Oversize 2)
  - Landscape studies
    - United States
      - The Apache Trail, Arizona, 1929 (Oversize 3)
      - A Blekinge Motif, Sweden, 1938 (Oversize 3)
      - Cathedral Rock, Bryce Canyon (Oversize 3)
      - Chapetepec (i.e., Chapultepec) Park, Mexico City (Oversize 3)
      - The Cloisters at Tzintzuntzan, Mexico (Oversize 3)
      - Cypresses at Monterrey, California (Oversize 3)
      - El Capitan, Yosemite Valley, 1923 (Oversize 3)
      - Esteys (i.e., Estes) National Park, a pinhole exposure, made without a lens (Oversize 3)
      - Grand Canyon at Dawn (Oversize 3)
      - The Great White Thrown (i.e., Throne), Zion National Park, 1930 (Oversize 3)
      - Live Oaks, Georgia (Oversize 3)
      - Pier at Murray Bay, 1928 (Oversize 3)
      - St. Mary's Lake, Glacier National Park, 1930 (Oversize 3)
      - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1949 (Oversize 3)
      - Sentinel at Sunset, Zion National Park, 1930 (Oversize 3)
      - Street in Urapan, Mexico, 1932 (Oversize 3)
      - Sunday Morning, South Ferry (Oversize 3)
      - Taos, New Mexico, 1930 (Oversize 3)
      - The Tennessee River, 1930 (Oversize 3)
      - Tree (two prints) (Oversize 3)
      - Wreck at Virginia Beach, 1930 (Oversize 3)
    - Canada
      - British Columbia, 1923 (Oversize 4)
      - Canadian North West, 1923 (Oversize 4)
      - Church with Daisies, Gaspe Peninsula, 1922 (Oversize 4)
      - Drying Cod, Gaspe Peninsula, 1923 (Oversize 4)
      - Daisies Along the Gaspe, 1923 (Oversize 4)
      - Lake Louise, Canadian Rockies (Oversize 4)
      - The Tower of Babel, Canadian Rockies, 1930 (Oversize 4)
      - The Valley of the Ten Peaks, British Columbia, 1923 (Oversize 4)
    - Vermont
      - Barns in Winter, Vermont, 1921 (Oversize 4)
      - Covered Bridges at Fairlee, Vermont (Oversize 4)
      - House in Winter, Thetford, Vermont (Oversize 4)
      - June in Vermont, 1920 (Oversize 4)
      - Old Bennington Church, Vermont, 1939 (Oversize 4)
      - The Old Darling Place, Dorset, Vermont *, 1927 (Oversize 4)
      - Thetford Hill Church, Vermont (Oversize 4)
      - House in Thetford, Vermont (Oversize 4)
      - Vermont Farm (Oversize 5)
      - The White Birch, Vermont (Oversize 5)
      - Winter Sunset, Vermont (Oversize 5)
      - Winter Woods, Vermont (Oversize 5)
    - Yugoslavia
      - An Abandoned Garden in Dalmatia, 1926 (Oversize 5)
      - Bay of Kotor (Oversize 5)
      - Ancient Bridge at Salona (Oversize 5)
      - Cypresses (Oversize 5)
      - Olive Grove, Dalmatia, 1926 (Oversize 5)
      - Pineas, Dalmation Coast (Oversize 5)
      - Plitvitsi Lake, 1926 (Oversize 5)
      - A Street in Sarajevo, 1926 (Oversize 5)
      - Where the Sava and the Danube Meet, Belgrade (Oversize 5)
  - Portrait studies
    Individuals are listed in alphabetical order by surname. Names are given as written on the item. For names that are illegible, incomplete, or incorrect, staff have attempted to correct/identify; this added information is given in square brackets, for example "Father [Sergei] Bulgakov".
    - Felix Adler, founder of Ethical Culture Movement (Oversize 6)
    - Jeanne Andonian, French novelist [wrote as Janine May], 1961 (Oversize 6)
    - D'Archiadi, [Archimede?] Rome (Oversize 6)
    - Dr. Azaioli of Rome, 1935 (Oversize 6)
    - Tokuho Azuma IV, Japanese Kabuki Theatre (Oversize 6)
    - Count Folke Bernadotte of Sweden, 1939 (Oversize 6)
    - Henry Beston, writer, 1952 (Oversize 6)
    - Paul Boepple, conductor, 1963 (Oversize 6)
    - Mme. [Catherine] Breshkovsky, "The Little Grandmother of the Russian Revolution" (Oversize 6)
    - Pearl Buck, writer (Oversize 6)
    - Pearl Buck, 1962 (Oversize 6)
    - Father [Sergei] Bulgakov, head of the Russian Orthodox Church in Paris, 1940 (Oversize 6)
    - Rudolf Bultmann, German theologian (Oversize 6)
    - Mrs. Rudolf Bultmann [Helene Feldmann ], 1958 (Oversize 6)
    - Ralph Bunche, statesman * (Oversize 6)
    - Charles Burchfield, painter, includes one print made by SCRC (Oversize 6)
    - H.R.H. Prince Carl of Sweden, head of the International Red Cross, 1938 (Oversize 6)
    - Chen Chi, Chinese, painter (Oversize 6)
    - Kate Chittenden, pianist and teacher, 1920 (Oversize 6)
    - Mabel Churchill, Syracuse, New York, teacher (Oversize 7)
    - Sally Cleghorn, poet (Oversize 7)
    - Elizabeth Coatsworth, writer (Oversize 7)
    - Charles Coburn in "The Better 'Ole" (Oversize 7)
    - Timothy Cole, wood engraver (Oversize 7)
    - Royal Cortissoz, art critic (Oversize 7)
    - John Cotton Dana, librarian [missing as of 2/2009] (Oversize 7)
    - Clarence Day, Woodstock, Vermont, 1920 (Oversize 7)
    - Robert W. de Forest, President of Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1922 (Oversize 7)
    - John Dewey, philosopher and educator * (Oversize 7)
    - Mary Dewson, Head of Women's Democratic Party under Roosevelt (Oversize 7)
    - W.E.B. DuBois, Negro writer, includes 4 prints made by SCRC (Oversize 7)
    - Irwin Edman, philosopher (Oversize 7)
    - Gustav Ekstein, writer (Oversize 7)
    - Carl Eldh, Swedish sculptor (Oversize 7)
    - Stuart Eldridge, Vermont artist, 1961 (Oversize 7)
    - H.R.H. Prince Eugene of Sweden (Oversize 7)
    - Phyllis Fenner, librarian, 1944 (Oversize 8)
    - John Finley, editor of the New York Times (Oversize 8)
    - Dorothy Canfield Fisher, writer (Oversize 8)
    - Michel Fokine, Russian choreographer and dancer [Mikhail Mikhaylovich Fokine] (Oversize 8)
    - Dr. Mary Freeman, 1955 (Oversize 8)
    - Robert Frost, poet, bust (Oversize 8)
    - Robert Frost, poet, full length (Oversize 8)
    - Robert Frost, Vermont poet, half length, 1953; includes one print made by SCRC (Oversize 8)
      See also Carl Ruggles.
    - Masaya Fujima II, Japanese Kabuki Theatre (Oversize 8)
    - Maria Germanova, Moscow Art Theatre (Oversize 8)
    - Lillian Galbraith [Gilbreth], engineer (Oversize 8)
    - Carol Glenn, violinist (Oversize 8)
    - Alexander Gretchaninov [Aleksandr Grechaninov], Russian composer, 1923 (Oversize 8)
    - Georges Gretanshikoff [Greshnikoff?], See Nicolas Roerich and Georges Gretanshikoff [Greshnikoff?].
    - Prof. Axel Hägerström, Swedish philosopher (Oversize 8)
    - Count Hugo Hamilton of Sweden, 1931 (Oversize 8)
    - Dag Hammarskjöld, Swedish statesman (Oversize 8)
    - Governor Professor Hjalmar Hammarskjöld (Oversize 8)
    - Walter Hard, poet (Oversize 8)
    - Roy Harris, composer (Oversize 8)
    - Roland Hayes (Oversize 8)
    - Liverpool Hazard, 108 years old (former slave on Butler Plantation, Georgia) (Oversize 8)
    - Professor Eli Heckscher, Swedish economic historian, 1938 (Oversize 8)
    - Granville Hicks, writer (Oversize 9)
    - Malvina Hoffman, sculptor (Oversize 9)
    - The last portrait of Oliver Wendell Holmes, three weeks before he died, 1935 (Oversize 9)
    - Langston Hughes, poet, includes one print made by SCRC (Oversize 9)
    - Charles Edward Ives, composer (Oversize 9)
    - Robinson Jeffers, poet, 1944 (Oversize 9)
    - Gertrude Käsebier, photographer (Oversize 9)
    - Vassily Kachalov, actor, Moscow Art Theatre, 1925 (Oversize 9)
    - Miss Kendall, Wellesley College professor, 1930s (Oversize 9)
    - Charles Rann Kennedy, playwright, 1920 (Oversize 9)
    - John Kirkpatrick, pianist (Oversize 9)
    - Knipper-Chekova, Olga, Moscow Art Theatre (Oversize 9)
    - Sergei Konenkov, Russian sculptor (Oversize 9)
    - Louis Krasner, violinist, includes two additional prints (Oversize 9)
    - Mr. & Mrs. Henry Lanier, son of Sidney Lanier, 1915 (Oversize 9)
    - Bruno Liljefors, Swedish nature painter (Oversize 9)
    - Eugene List, pianist, 1961 (Oversize 9)
    - Amy Loveman, editor, Saturday Review, 1952 (Oversize 9)
    - Luigi in the Birch Wood, Manchester, Vt., 1951; Luigi Lucioni, painter (Oversize 9)
    - Toni at Taos, 1949 (Oversize 9)
    - Edwin Markham, poet (Oversize 10)
    - Anjani Mehta of India, 1947 (Oversize 10)
    - Ivan Mestrovic in his studio at Zagreb, Yugoslavia, 1924 (Oversize 10)
    - Ivan Mestrovic, Yugoslav sculptor, includes one print made by SCRC (Oversize 10)
    - Carl Milles, Swedish sculptor (Oversize 10)
    - Emma Mills, book reviewer, 1952 (Oversize 10)
    - Grandma Moses, painter (Oversize 10)
    - Ivan Moskvin as Tsar Feodor, Moscow Art Theatre, 1926 (Oversize 10)
    - Ivan Moskvin, Moscow Art Theatre (Oversize 10)
    - Boris Nagashoff (Oversize 10)
    - Isamu Noguchi, sculptor, includes one print made by SCRC (Oversize 10)
    - Paul Ouzounoff, artist, Moscow Art Theatre (Oversize 10)
    - Mme. Isabella de Palencia, Spanish Ambassador to Sweden, 1941 (Oversize 10)
    - Kurt Palm of Sweden, 1939 (Oversize 10)
    - Roland Palmedo, 1940 (Oversize 10)
    - Mme. [Vijaya Lakshmi] Pandit, India, 1946 (Oversize 10)
    - Anne Parrish, writer, 1940 (Oversize 10)
    - Frances Perkins, Secretary of Labor (Oversize 11)
    - Dr. Samuel Pettingill of Vermont, 1959 (Oversize 11)
    - Clarence Pickett, Quaker leader (Oversize 11)
    - Sergei Rachmaninoff, Russian composer and pianist (Oversize 11)
    - Sir Sarvepali Radhakrishnan, President of India (Oversize 11)
    - Carl Ramsay, orchidist, 1956 (Oversize 11)
    - Ellen Emmet Rand, portrait painter, 1940 (Oversize 11)
    - Santha Rama Rau, Indian writer (Oversize 11)
    - Sigmund [Syngman] Rhee of Korea, 1941 (Oversize 11)
    - Mme. [Natalia] Rimsky-Korsakoff, niece of Tschaikovsky (Oversize 11)
    - Nicolas Roerich [Nikolai Konstantinovich Rerikh] and Georges Gretanshikoff [Greshnikoff?], 1922 (Oversize 11)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt, humanitarian, includes one print made by SCRC (Oversize 11)
    - Mrs. Theodore Roosevelt Jr., 1920 (Oversize 11)
    - Glen Rounds, writer & artist, 1953 (Oversize 11)
    - Dane Rudyar [Rudhyar], theosophist (Oversize 11)
    - Carl Ruggles and Robert Frost, 1958 (Oversize 11)
    - Ruth St. Denis, dancer (Oversize 12)
    - Mrs. Sampson, 1953 (Oversize 12)
    - Lawrence Schmeckebier, Art Department, Syracuse University (Oversize 12)
    - Albert Schweitzer, writer-doctor-philosopher-musician (Oversize 12)
    - Rudolf Serkin, pianist (Oversize 12)
    - Roger Sessions, composer (Oversize 12)
    - Otis Skinner, actor (Oversize 12)
    - John Sloan, painter (Oversize 12)
    - Mr. Speed of Union Village, Vermont (Oversize 12)
    - Constantin Stanislavsky, Founder of Moscow Art Theatre (Oversize 12)
    - Alfred Stieglitz, photographer, includes two prints made by SCRC (Oversize 12)
    - Sadja, daughter of Leopold Stokowski (Oversize 12)
    - Harlan Fiske Stone, Chief Justice of the United States Supreme Court (Oversize 12)
    - Lorado Taft, sculptor (Oversize 12)
    - Tane Takahashi of Japan, 1953 (Oversize 12)
    - Ida Tarbell, author, 1942 (Oversize 12)
    - Mrs. Truscott of Thetford, Vermont, 1921 (Oversize 12)
    - Elizabeth Gray Vining, writer (Oversize 12)
    - Wang, Chinese painter, 1942 (Oversize 12)
    - Edward Weston, photographer (Oversize 12)
    - Gladys White (Mrs Walter White) (Oversize 12)
    - Walter White, American Negro leader (Oversize 12)
    - Frances Williams, actress, 1951 (Oversize 12)
    - Eleanor Worcester of Vermont, 1925 (Oversize 12)
    - Mrs. Wyman of Vermont, 1962; neighbor (Oversize 12)
    - Stanley Yarnall, Quaker teacher, 1958 (Oversize 12)
    - Junzo Yoshimura, Japanese architect, 1945 (Oversize 12)
    - Ella Young, Irish folklorist, 1949 (Oversize 12)
    - Marguerite Zorach, artist (Oversize 12)
    - Unidentified (Oversize 12)
  - Still life studies
    - Apple (Oversize 13)
    - An Arrangement of Woodbine and Glass, 1929 (Oversize 13)
    - The Bibles of Rufus Jones (Oversize 13)
    - Fading Roses (Oversize 13)
    - Floating Hollyhocks (Oversize 13)
    - Freeshia [sic], 1923 (Oversize 13)
    - Freesias (Oversize 13)
    - Ivy and Old Glass, 1920 (Oversize 13)
    - Ivy in Old Bottle, 1920 (Oversize 13)
    - Jack in the Pulpit, 1922 (Oversize 13)
    - Mother by Mestrovic (Oversize 13)
    - [sculpture] by Mestrovic (Oversize 14)
    - Paganini by Konenkov, 1921 (Oversize 13)
    - Rose in Glass Bottle, 1922 (Oversize 13)
    - Roses and Steps, 1922 (Oversize 13)
    - Spring Arrangement (Oversize 13)
      See also Spring Bloom in Glass Container.
    - Spring Beauties, 1922 (Oversize 13)
    - Spring Bloom in Glass Container, 1922 (Oversize 13)
      See also Spring Arrangement.
    - Still Life Roses (Oversize 13)
    - Still Life with St. Francis, 1945 (Oversize 13)
    - Water Lily, 1929 (Oversize 13)
    - General Nicholas Khrahoff [Khrabroff?] (Oversize 14)
    - Felicity, 1968 (Oversize 14)
    - Kristi, 1969 (Oversize 14)
    - Sergei Konenkov, Russian sculptor (Oversize 14)
    - New York Harbor (Oversize 14)
    - Carol Fenner (Oversize 14)
    - Lorado Taft and a section of his Fountain of Time on Chicago midway (Oversize 14)
    - Jennifer, 1969 (Oversize 14)
    - Svetlana Alleluyeva [daughter of Josef Stalin] (Oversize 14)
    - Welthy Honsinger Fisher, Founder of Literacy Village, Lucknow, India (Oversize 14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - An Arrangement with Frog, 1922 (Oversize 15)
    - Albert Einstein, physicist (framed) (Oversize 15)
- Prints acquired separately
  - Woman in canoe, carbon print, mounted between glass plates; source unknown; note reads "Ackerman preservation" (Box 70)
  - Unidentified woman (Box 70)
    Gift of Richard Kremer, 2003.
  - Unidentified woman, possibly Antje Lemke; proofs, badly discolored (Box 70)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959-1960; undated; Granville Hicks, Roger Sessions, landscapes, library, books; 3 are platinum prints (Box 70)
- Miscellaneous
  - Articles, 1926; 1958 (Box 70)
  - Clippings, 1975-1976; 1980,; undated (Box 70)
  - Exhibit catalogs, 1970; 1979,; 1987; 3 folders (Box 71)
  - File index [created by SCRC?] (Box 73)
  - Clara E. Sipprell: Photo-pictorialist by Mary McCabe, 1985; dissertation (Box 71)
    Gift of Mary McCabe, 1985.
  - Miscellaneous, includes Sipprell's business card and brochure (Box 71)